<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>https://docs.technotim.live/</id><title>Techno Tim Documentation</title><subtitle>Documentation for Techno Tim YouTube videos for all your copy pasta needs!</subtitle> <updated>2023-03-09T19:47:52-06:00</updated> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> <uri>https://docs.technotim.live/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://docs.technotim.live/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" href="https://docs.technotim.live/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2023 Techno Tim </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Rotating your Encryption Keys and Updating your Secrets with SOPS</title><link href="https://docs.technotim.live/posts/rotate-sops-encryption-keys/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rotating your Encryption Keys and Updating your Secrets with SOPS" /><published>2023-03-05T09:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2023-03-05T22:21:06-06:00</updated> <id>https://docs.technotim.live/posts/rotate-sops-encryption-keys/</id> <content src="https://docs.technotim.live/posts/rotate-sops-encryption-keys/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="utilities" /> <summary> If you’ve been encrypting your secrets with SOPS and Age you know how useful it is to keep your secrets safe from prying eyes. If you’re not familiar with encrypting your secrets with SOPS and Age, I highly recommend checking out a post I did a while back that shows you how easy it is to encrypt your secrets and even hide them in plain sight in a Git repo. I am happy (and relieved) that I star... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Configuring VLANs, Firewall Rules, and WiFi Networks - UniFi Network Application</title><link href="https://docs.technotim.live/posts/vlan-firewall-unifi/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Configuring VLANs, Firewall Rules, and WiFi Networks - UniFi Network Application" /><published>2023-03-04T09:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2023-03-09T19:47:34-06:00</updated> <id>https://docs.technotim.live/posts/vlan-firewall-unifi/</id> <content src="https://docs.technotim.live/posts/vlan-firewall-unifi/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> What is a VLAN and How Do They Help? Today we’re going to cover setting up VLANs using UniFi’s network controller. We’ll set up a VLAN, from start to finish, which includes creating a new network, configuring a wireless network that uses VLANs, and then we’ll set up firewall rules to make sure we’re keeping our network safe. If you think VLANs are only for the enterprise, you’re wrong, I wi... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>The Ultimate Guide to Wake on LAN for Windows, MacOS, and Linux</title><link href="https://docs.technotim.live/posts/wake-on-lan/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Ultimate Guide to Wake on LAN for Windows, MacOS, and Linux" /><published>2023-02-19T09:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2023-02-22T22:46:07-06:00</updated> <id>https://docs.technotim.live/posts/wake-on-lan/</id> <content src="https://docs.technotim.live/posts/wake-on-lan/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="utilities" /> <summary> What is Wake on LAN and why is it so hard? After releasing my video on the PiKVM I realized that there was so much confusion about Wake on LAN, and rightfully so, that I decided to put together this guide on how to configure Wake on LAN on any machine. Wake on LAN (WoL) is a networking standard that allows a computer to be turned on by sending a network packet. The client sends a special packe... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Using the Raspberry Pi PiKVM with Multiple Machines</title><link href="https://docs.technotim.live/posts/pikvm-at-scale/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using the Raspberry Pi PiKVM with Multiple Machines" /><published>2023-02-18T09:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2023-02-22T22:46:07-06:00</updated> <id>https://docs.technotim.live/posts/pikvm-at-scale/</id> <content src="https://docs.technotim.live/posts/pikvm-at-scale/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> What is the PiKVM? If you don’t know what a KVM switch is, it’s a device that allows you to connect multiple computers to one device which allows you to control them with a single keyboard, monitor, and mouse. They’re relatively cheap unless you’re looking for an IP based one that will let you connect over the network. IP KVMs are really expensive, that is until the PiKVM came along. The PiK... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Test Your Internet Speed from the Linux Terminal with fast</title><link href="https://docs.technotim.live/posts/fast-internet-test-cli/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Test Your Internet Speed from the Linux Terminal with fast" /><published>2023-02-05T09:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2023-02-20T21:58:05-06:00</updated> <id>https://docs.technotim.live/posts/fast-internet-test-cli/</id> <content src="https://docs.technotim.live/posts/fast-internet-test-cli/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="utilities" /> <summary> What is FAST.com? FAST.com is speed test gives you an estimate of your current Internet speed. It was created by Netflix to bring transparency to your upload / download speeds and to see if your ISP may be prioritizing traffic. I’ve run this quite a bit in a browser to do a quick spot check or my speeds, but I’ve never had a great tool to check this from some of my Linux machines. Let me cla... </summary> </entry> </feed>
